Alex Pawelczyk

(586) 344-2563 alex.pawelczyk@ uwaterloo.ca 44314 Saturn Dr, Sterling Heights, MI, 48314





Former semi-professional hockey player in the Quebec Major Junior Hockey League (QMJHL). Dalhousie University graduate with a Bachelor of Computer Science. Current graduate student and varsity hockey player at the David R. Cheriton School of Computer Science, University of Waterloo. Strong background in Java, JavaScript, Android development, Web development (HTML/CSS/Bootstrap), MySQL, and Firebase. Moderate background in C++, C, and Python. Strong workethic, leadership, and interpersonal skills acquired from 20+ years of playing competitive hockey and being a student athlete. Due to COVID-19, I am finishing my master's degree online and ready to start work immediately.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HOCKEY CAMP INSTRUCTOR

Dalhousie University / Halifax, NS / 2016-19

- Support and develop youth hockey and leadership skills
- Create practice plans for both on and off-ice sessions
- Demonstrate drills during on-ice sessions
- Communicate daily with children and parents
- Ensure all kids are accounted for and on-time for their daily events

SEMI-PROFESSIONAL HOCKEY PLAYER

Shawinigan Cataractes (QMJHL) / Shawinigan, QC / 2012-16

- Responsible for being on-time to all practices, games, and team functions
- Responsible for being a model citizen in the community
- Assistant captain for two seasons (2014-16)

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

- KWhabilitation Helping local farmers with manual labor (Waterloo, ON)
- Rink-Coordinator at the 2018 HFX Summer Classic Ball Hockey Tournament (Halifax, NS)
- Volunteered at the 2017 Dalhousie Black & Gold Club Banquet, as well as the 2016 Dalhousie Black & Gold Club Golf Tournament (Halifax, NS)
- Speaking to students at elementary schools about the importance of education (Shawinigan, QC)
- Public skates with fans, volunteer coaching, and a wide variety of other community events (Shawinigan, QC)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Check out some of my projects at my portfolio website

EDUCATION

MA Computer Science University of Waterloo, ON 2019-present

BA Computer Science Dalhousie University, NS 2016-19

General Studies

Athabasca University, AB

2013–16

High School Diploma The Keystone School 2012-13

KEY SKILLS

Communication

Leadership

Work Ethic

Java

Android

MySQL

AWARDS

3x USPORTS Academic All Canadian (2016-18, 2019-20)

Finalist for QMJHL Scholastic Player of the Year (2015)

> Varsity Hockey Athletic Scholarship (2016-20)